ただいま:Here I am/I'm home!|presently, おかえり:return|welcome home
(咲太)ただいま｡
(理央)おかえり｡
I'm home.
Welcome back.
カレー:curry, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
何してんの？
ｶﾚｰ作ってる｡
What are you doing?
Making curry.
In a lab coat?
格好[かっこう, かっこ]:shape|appearance|state||, カレー:curry, はねる:to jump/to leap|to break up, はねる:to hit (e.g. to have a car hit someone)/to run into|to reject, 嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
その格好で？
ｶﾚｰはねると嫌だし｡
Episode 8: Let the Rain Wash Everything Anew
I don't want it splattering on me.
This is good.
おいしい:delicious/tasty|attractive, うまい:skillful/skilful|delicious
(かえで)おいしいです！
うん うまいな｡
Yeah, it's tasty.
レシピ:recipe, どおり:in accordance with/following|roughly, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||, 当たり前[あたりまえ]:natural/reasonable|usual, 実験[じっけん]:experiment, 一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same
ﾚｼﾋﾟどおりに作ったから当たり前
実験と一緒｡
As it should be.
I followed the recipe exactly.
It's the same as a lab experiment.
Yeah, cooking and experiments are kind of similar.
確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken, 料理[りょうり]:cooking/cookery|dealing with something, 実験[じっけん]:experiment, 似る[にる]:to resemble/to look like|to be similar (in status, condition, etc.)
(麻衣)確かに 料理と実験って
似てるかもね｡
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
双葉 ちょっといいか？
Futaba, got a minute?
Why do you keep talking to me
while I'm in the bath?
ことごとく:altogether/entirely, 入浴[にゅうよく]:bathing|to bathe/to take a bath, 話しかける[はなしかける]:to address (someone)/to accost a person|to begin to talk
どうして ことごとく
入浴中に話しかけてくるわけ？
Because having only a door between me
and a naked girl is quite arousing.
一[いち]:one|best|first||, 一[ひとつ]:one|for one thing|only||, 枚[まい]:counter for flat objects (e.g. sheets of paper), 枚[びら, ビラ]:bill/handbill/flier, 向こう[むこう]:opposite side|over there|the other party|, 裸[はだか]:naked/nude/bare, 女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl
ﾄﾞｱ一枚向こうに
裸の女子がいるって
興奮[こうふん]:excitement/stimulation/agitation
興奮するから｡
Some things are easier to discuss
when you're not face-to-face, right?
顔が見える[かおがみえる]:identifiable/personalized, 話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language), やすい:cheap/inexpensive|calm, やすい:easy|likely to .../have a tendency to ...
顔が見えないほうが
話しやすいこともあるだろ｡
何それ｡
What the heck?
一人[ひとり, いちにん]:one person|alone/unmarried, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
もう一人の双葉がやってることは
知ってる｡
I found out what the other Futaba's been doing.
Selfie 70
Selfie 69
偽者[にせもの]:impostor/imposter/pretender
偽者から何か聞いたんだ｡
The fake told you about it?
多少[たしょう]:more or less/somewhat|amount, 経緯[いきさつ, けいい]:details|longitude and latitude|warp and weft, 複雑[ふくざつ]:complex/complicated/mixed (feelings)
いや 多少 経緯は
複雑なんだけどさ｡
Nah, but how I found out is a long story.
アカウント:account, 夏休み[なつやすみ]:summer vacation/summer holiday, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
ｱｶｳﾝﾄは夏休み前から作ってた｡
I created the account before summer break,
書く[かく]:to write/to compose|to draw
でも 何を書けばいいか
わからなかった｡
but I didn't know what to post.
Anything would've done.
何でもよかったんじゃないの？
持ち[もち]:hold|wear|usage, イケメン:good-looking guy/handsome man/hunk, 恋[こい]:(romantic) love
今 彼女持ちのｲｹﾒﾝに
恋してます とかさ｡
Like, "I'm in love with a hot guy
who has a girlfriend."
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, ネット:network, 友達[ともだち]:friend/companion, 作る[つくる]:to make|to prepare (food)|to raise||
双葉は ﾈｯﾄで
お友達を作ろうとしたのか？
Were you trying to make friends online?
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 単純[たんじゅん]:simplicity/simple/uncomplicated
どうだろ… もっと単純に
I don't know.
Maybe I simply wanted some attention.
かまう:to mind/to care about|to care for
誰かに
かまってほしかっただけかもね｡
Posting lewd stuff from the get-go is cheating, you know?
最初[さいしょ]:beginning/outset/first, 投稿[とうこう]:contribution/submission/posting (e.g. to a newsgroup or mailing list), ずるい:sly/cunning|miserly
最初からｴﾛﾈﾀの投稿はずるいだろ｡
That's all I have.
私には それしかないんだよ｡
むしろ:rather/better/instead, むしろ:woven mat (esp. one made of straw)|seat, 自信[じしん]:self-confidence/confidence (in oneself)
むしろ そこは自信あったのか｡
Proud of your body, huh?
自信[じしん]:self-confidence/confidence (in oneself), どころ:particle used to indicate that what precedes it is an extreme example and strongly negates it, コンプレックス:complex
自信どころか ｺﾝﾌﾟﾚｯｸｽにしか
思ってなかった｡
Hardly. I actually developed
an inferiority complex over it.
同級生[どうきゅうせい]:classmate, 女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl, 部分[ぶぶん]:portion/section/part, 成長[せいちょう]:growth/grow to adulthood, 早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|
同級生より 女子の部分の成長は
早かったから｡
My lady parts developed much earlier
than other girls my age.
同然[どうぜん]:similar to/same/right, 男子[だんし]:youth/young man, どういう:somehow/how/in what way
それをｻﾙ同然の男子たちが
どういう目で見てたかを知って
Once I learned that the boys
were ogling me like apes,
体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 嫌い[きらい]:dislike|suspicion|distinction, 嫌い[ぎらい]:dislike/hatred/fear
この体が嫌いになった｡
I came to hate this body.
汚れる[けがれる]:to be violated/to be corrupted/to be polluted, 汚れる[よごれる]:to get dirty/to become dirty|to become sullied, 思える[おもえる]:to seem/to appear likely
自分が汚れたもののように
思えてきて…｡
It made me feel filthy.
And you still posted those pics?
写真[しゃしん]:photograph/photo|movie, 反応[はんのう, はんおう]:reaction/response
なのに あの写真か｡
反応があるから｡
It gets reactions.
相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.), 反応[はんのう, はんおう]:reaction/response
相手が誰であれ
反応があるだけで
Just getting reactions from people,
whoever they were, put me at ease.
救う[すくう]:to rescue from/to help out of/to save, 気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|
救われた気持ちになれた｡
You sure make it sound like
that's not how you wanted it.
望む[のぞむ]:to desire|to wish for|to see, かたち:form/shape|visage, 同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway
それ 望んだかたちじゃないって
言ってるのと同じだぞ｡
結局[けっきょく]:after all|conclusion|ending of a game of Go, 嫌悪[けんお]:disgust/hate/repugnance, 感[かん]:feeling/sensation|interjection
だからかもね 結局
見られることへの嫌悪感は
Maybe that's why.
I couldn't shake off my
dislike of being ogled,
捨てる[すてる]:to throw away|to abandon|to give up, 相[さが, なりくせ]:one's nature/one's destiny|custom, 相[あい]:together/mutually/fellow, 反する[はんする]:to be contrary to|to act contrary to (rules or guidelines)|to oppose, 目的[もくてき]:purpose/goal/aim, 手段[しゅだん]:means/way/measure, 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room
捨てられなかったから…
相反する目的と手段の間に
and the stress I felt from my conflicting goals and means
強烈[きょうれつ]:strong/intense/severe, ストレス:stress, 感ずる[かんずる]:to feel/to sense, 乖離[かいり]:divergence/alienation/deviation
強烈なｽﾄﾚｽを感じていたことが
私を乖離させた｡
made me dissociate.
So basically, the attention-
seeking you over there
かまう:to mind/to care about|to care for, あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
つまり 誰かにかまってほしい
あっちの双葉と
手段[しゅだん]:means/way/measure, 許す[ゆるす]:to permit|to exempt (from fine)|to confide in|, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
そのための手段が許せない
こっちの双葉が
and the you here, who couldn't
accept those methods, split up?
分離[ぶんり]:separation/partition/detachment, たって:strongly hoping or requesting (of something that is difficult to be brought to fruition), たって:even if/even though|however, だいたい:outline/main point|general, だいたい:battalion, 合う[あう, おう]:to come together|to fit|to be profitable|
分離したってことか？
だいたい合ってる｡
That's more or less right.
一人[ひとり, いちにん]:one person|alone/unmarried, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 自[じ, ころ]:self-|from ...|this ... (in contrast to some other ...), 撮る[とる]:to take (a photo)|to record (video, audio, etc.)/to make (a film), アップ:increasing
もう一人の双葉は
自撮りのｱｯﾌﾟ
It looks like the other you's
still putting up those selfies.
続ける[つづける]:to continue/to keep up/to keep on, みたい:-like/sort of/similar to
まだ続けてるみたいだぞ｡
わかってる…｡
I know.
What do you want to do?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, させる:to make (someone) do|to allow (someone) to, させる:(usu. followed by a negative form) worth special consideration
双葉は どうしたいんだ？
できるなら やめさせたい｡
I want to make her stop, if possible.
任せる[まかせる]:to entrust (e.g. a task) to another|to passively leave to someone else's facilities|to leave to take its natural course||
わかった 任せとけ｡
All right.
I've got you.
What are you thinking?
気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of, 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, 学校[がっこう]:school
どうする気？
明日も学校に行くよ｡
I'll go to school again tomorrow.
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, だらだら:in drops/dripping|gently (sloping), 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
それで あっちの双葉と
だらだら話でもしてくる｡
And I'll talk to the other you all day.
面倒[めんどう]:trouble|trouble|care, くさい:stinking/smelly|suspicious, くさい:salvation (from suffering based on Buddha's teachings)
面倒くさいことするね｡
That sounds like effort.
What's your favorite thing, Doka-chan?
好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
どかちゃん 好きなものは？
(のどか)はい
Oh, it's Sakurajima Mai, the actress.
女優[じょゆう]:actress, 桜[さくら, サクラ]:cherry tree|decoy|hired applauder|, 島[しま]:island|territory (of a prostitute, organized crime gang, etc.)/turf, 島[とう]:Island|insula/island, 麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe
女優の桜島麻衣さんです｡
You're calling her a thing?
テレビ:television/TV, 扱い[あつかい]:treatment/service, 普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train, イチゴ:strawberry (esp. the garden strawberry, Fragaria x ananassa), 豆[まめ]:legume (esp. edible legumes or their seeds, such as beans, peas, pulses, etc.)|soya bean (Glycine max)|female genitalia (esp. the clitoris)||, 大福[だいふく]:great fortune/good luck|rice cake stuffed with bean jam, 大福[おおぶく, だいぶく]:swallowing a great amount of tea or medicine|tea prepared for the New Year with the first water of the year
[ﾃﾚﾋﾞ]もの扱い？ そこは 普通
ｲﾁｺﾞとか豆大福とか
Normally, one would say something like
"strawberries" or "bean daifuku"...
答える[こたえる]:to answer/to reply, 麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 風呂[ふろ]:bath|bathroom|room for drying lacquerware|
答えるところでしょ｡
麻衣さん お風呂はどうします？
Mai-san, do you want to
take a bath here or what?
Well, before that...
うん その前に…｡
Oh, come to think of it, you said you wanted to talk to me about something.
話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
あっ そういえば なんか
話あるって言ってましたよね｡
デート:date/go on a date, 禁止[きんし]:prohibition/inhibition/ban, 別れる[わかれる]:to part (usu. of people)|to separate (of a couple)|to lose (e.g. one's mother)
えっ ﾃﾞｰﾄ禁止!?
それって別れろってことですか？
What? No dates?
Are they telling us to break up?
They didn't go that far,
そこまでは言われなかったけど
しばらく:little while/short while|a while, 事務所[じむしょ]:office, 命令[めいれい]:order/command|(software) instruction
しばらくは ２人で
会わないようにって 事務所命令｡
but the agency says we shouldn't meet alone for a while.
恋愛[れんあい]:love/love-making/passion, 禁止[きんし]:prohibition/inhibition/ban, アイドル:young star/young entertainer/heartthrob
ﾊｧ…｡
私のこと 恋愛禁止のｱｲﾄﾞﾙと
Maybe they think I'm one of those idols they can ban from dating.
勘違い[かんちがい]:misunderstanding/wrong guess
勘違いしてるのかもね｡
And you agreed?
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 承諾[しょうだく]:consent/acquiescence/agreement
それで麻衣さんは
承諾したんですか？
一人[ひとり, いちにん]:one person|alone/unmarried, 決める[きめる]:to decide|to clinch (a victory)|to persist in doing||, 問題[もんだい]:question (e.g. on a test)|problem (e.g. societal, political)|question (i.e. doubt)||
私一人で決めていい
問題じゃないから
It's not my decision to make alone,
so I put it on hold.
保留[ほりゅう]:reserve/putting on hold|hold (e.g. telephone button)
保留にしてある｡
You mean...
問題[もんだい]:question (e.g. on a test)|problem (e.g. societal, political)|question (i.e. doubt)||
それって…｡
そっ ２人の問題でしょ？
Exactly. It's our decision to make.
I think we'll have to play along for now.
しばらく:little while/short while|a while, 仕方ない[しかたない]:it can't be helped/it's inevitable/it's no use
しばらくは
仕方ないんじゃないですか｡
What do you mean,
we'll have to play along?
仕方ない[しかたない]:it can't be helped/it's inevitable/it's no use, 戦略的[せんりゃくてき]:strategic, 撤退[てったい]:evacuation/withdrawal/revocation
なによ 仕方ないって｡
戦略的撤退です｡
We'll make a tactical retreat.
しばらく:little while/short while|a while, 会[え]:gathering (esp. Buddhist, festive, etc.), 会[かい]:meeting/assembly|association
咲太はいいの？
しばらく私と会えなくなっても｡
Are you really okay with
not seeing me for a while?
Absolutely not.
嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
嫌ですよ｡
But you only just got back into showbiz,
芸能[げいのう]:public entertainment/performing arts|accomplishments, 活動[かつどう]:action/activity|movie (esp. during the silent movie period), 再開[さいかい]:reopening/resumption/restarting, 間[あいだ, あわい]:space (between)|time (between)|span (temporal or spatial)||, 間[ま]:time|space|room
でも 芸能活動を再開して
間もないんですから
しばらく:little while/short while|a while, 優等生[ゆうとうせい]:honor student/honours student
しばらくは優等生でいたほうが
so you'd probably make a better impression
by being a good girl for now.
周囲[しゅうい]:surroundings/environs|circumference
周囲のｳｹも
いいんじゃないですか？
That's so sensible it's kinda lame.
つまる:to be packed (with)/to be full (space, schedule, etc.)|to be blocked (road, pipe, etc.), 正論[せいろん]:sound argument/fair argument/just reasoning
つまんない正論｡
August 4th
何かわかった？
Learn anything?
Only that you've got a bombshell hidden under those clothes.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 脱ぐ[ぬぐ]:to take off (clothes, shoes, etc.)/to undress, すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength)
双葉が脱ぐと
すごいってことがわかった｡
真似[まね, マネ]:imitating/copying|behavior
(理央)それで 梓川は
ﾊﾞｶな真似するなって
So, you came to yell at me
not to do these stupid things?
説教[せっきょう]:propounding/preaching|remonstration, 面倒[めんどう]:trouble|trouble|care, くさい:stinking/smelly|suspicious, くさい:salvation (from suffering based on Buddha's teachings)
説教しにきたんだ｡
するか 面倒くさい｡
As if. That's too much effort.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe, 帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home, デート:date/go on a date
麻衣さんは帰っちゃったし
ﾃﾞｰﾄもできないしで
Since Mai-san went home
and we can't go on dates,
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, だらだら:in drops/dripping|gently (sloping), 過ごす[すごす]:to pass (time)|to overdo (esp. of one's alcohol consumption)|to take care of||
ﾋﾏだから 双葉と
だらだら過ごそうと思ってさ｡
I have nothing to do,
so I came to chill all day with you.
I see. So you came to do something that takes even more effort.
なるほど:I see/That's right!/Indeed, もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 面倒[めんどう]:trouble|trouble|care, くさい:stinking/smelly|suspicious, くさい:salvation (from suffering based on Buddha's teachings)
なるほど もっと面倒くさいことを
しにきたんだ｡
Did you take more pics?
Other than the ones you uploaded.
他[ほか]:other (place, thing, person)|outside|nothing except|, 他[た]:other (esp. people and abstract matters), 撮る[とる]:to take (a photo)|to record (video, audio, etc.)/to make (a film), アップ:increasing, 以外[いがい]:with the exception of/excepting
他にも撮ってるのか？
ｱｯﾌﾟしたやつ以外に｡
They're not all lewd, huh?
エロい:erotic/pornographic|eminent, ばっか:only/merely|approximately
ｴﾛいのばっかじゃないんだな｡
中学[ちゅうがく]:middle school/junior high school
それは中学の｡
Those are from middle school.
最初[さいしょ]:beginning/outset/first, 見せる[みせる]:to show/to display, 気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
最初は 誰かに
見せたりする気なんてなかった｡
At first, I had no intention of showing anyone.
客観的[きゃっかんてき]:objective
客観的に自分を見て
ﾊﾞｶなことしてるって
I think I just wanted a way to look at myself
and go, "Wow, what a fool."
思いたかっただけなんだと思う｡
What does that even achieve?
一種[いっしゅ, ひとくさ]:species/kind/variety, 自傷[じしょう]:self-mutilation/self-injury, 行為[こうい]:act/deed/conduct
それ 何のためだよ｡
一種の自傷行為｡
It's a form of self-harm.
理解[りかい]:understanding/comprehension/appreciation, しれる:to become known/to come to light|to be known
梓川には
理解できないかもしれないけど
You may not understand,
嫌い[きらい]:dislike|suspicion|distinction, 嫌い[ぎらい]:dislike/hatred/fear
私は 私が嫌いなんだよ｡
but I hate myself.
一人[ひとり, いちにん]:one person|alone/unmarried, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 似る[にる]:to resemble/to look like|to be similar (in status, condition, etc.)
もう一人の双葉も
似たようなこと言ってたな｡
The other you said something similar.
Whose side are you on?
どっち:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives), 味方[みかた]:friend/ally/supporter
梓川はさ どっちの味方なの？
I'm on Futaba's side.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 味方[みかた]:friend/ally/supporter, こざかしい:clever/shrewd/crafty, 答え[こたえ, いらえ]:answer/reply/response
僕は 双葉の味方だ｡
こざかしい答えだね｡
Very funny, wise guy.
You should give up on one of us.
どっち:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives), 諦める[あきらめる]:to give up/to abandon (hope, plans)/to resign oneself (to)
梓川も どっちかを
諦めたほうがいいよ｡
世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
この世界に 双葉理央は
２人もいらない｡
This world isn't big enough for two Futaba Rios.
I went to Kamakura.
鎌倉[かまくら]:Kamakura (city), あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener)
鎌倉まで行ってきた｡
あっちの私と？
With the other me?
Nah, alone.
だらだら:in drops/dripping|gently (sloping), 話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language)
いや １人で｡
だらだら話すんじゃなかったの？
What happened to talking to her all day?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
なぁ 双葉 どうすれば
１人に戻ると思う？
Say, Futaba.
How do you think you'll go back to being one?
別々[べつべつ]:separately/individually, 記憶[きおく]:memory/recollection|storage, 経験[けいけん]:experience, バラバラ:scattered/disperse/loose, 以上[いじょう]:not less than|beyond ... (e.g. one's means)|above-mentioned||
２人が別々のことをして
記憶と経験もﾊﾞﾗﾊﾞﾗになった以上
Now that we've done different things
and our memories and
experiences have diverged,
一[いち]:one|best|first||, 一[ひとつ]:one|for one thing|only||, 戻す[もどす]:to put back|to vomit|to recover (of a market price), 気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of
一つに戻せる気はしない｡
I don't feel like we even can
become one again.
August 5th
Well?
どっち:which way/which direction|which one (esp. of two alternatives), 決まる[きまる]:to be decided/to be settled|to look good in (clothes)
で どっちの私にするかは
決まった？
Have you decided which one yet?
Decide that yourself.
決める[きめる]:to decide|to clinch (a victory)|to persist in doing||
そんなもん 自分で決めろ｡
This is your problem, not mine.
決める[きめる]:to decide|to clinch (a victory)|to persist in doing||
自分のことは
自分で決めるもんだろ｡
True. Good point.
なるほど:I see/That's right!/Indeed, 正論[せいろん]:sound argument/fair argument/just reasoning
なるほど 正論だね｡
I'm gonna die.
風[ふり]:swing|appearance|pretence (pretense)||, 風[かぜ]:wind|manner|cold, プリーズ:please
(国見)あ～ もう死ぬ～
咲太 風ﾌﾟﾘｰｽﾞ｡
Sakuta, breeze please.
Futaba, Kunimi wants you to fan him.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, あおぐ:to look up (at)|to look up (to)/to respect, あおぐ:to fan|to incite/to instigate
双葉 国見があおいでくれってさ｡
Futaba, breeze please.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 風[ふり]:swing|appearance|pretence (pretense)||, 風[かぜ]:wind|manner|cold, プリーズ:please
双葉 風ﾌﾟﾘｰｽﾞ｡
Man...
気持ち[きもち]:feeling|preparedness|thanks|
あ～ 気持ちいい！
That feels good.
Do you want some, Rio-san?
食べる[たべる]:to eat|to live on (e.g. a salary)/to live off
理央さんも食べませんか？
うん…｡
Yeah...
続ける[つづける]:to continue/to keep up/to keep on, 気[き]:spirit|nature|motivation||, 気[げ]:seeming/giving the appearance of/giving one the feeling of
(理央)で 梓川は いつまで
こんなことを続ける気？
And?
How long are you going to keep this up?
August 12th
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25)
双葉が あんなことを
しないようになるまでかな｡
Until you stop doing what you're doing, I guess?
画像[がぞう]:image/picture/portrait
僕だけに ｴﾛ画像を
Or maybe until you decide you'll only show your lewd pics to me.
見せる[みせる]:to show/to display
見せてくれるようになるまででも
いいけどさ｡
日々[ひび, にちにち]:every day/daily/day after day, 目標[めじるし]:mark/sign/landmark, 目標[もくひょう]:mark/objective/target, 遠のく[とおのく]:to become distant/to recede
それだと 日々
目標から遠のいてるね｡
That means your goal is growing more distant by the day.
Did someone respond?
誰かのﾚｽ？
Those are some hella lewd photos, lol
That's Minegahara High's uniform, right?!
I'm nearby. Wanna meet up?
Where are you?
If you blow me off, I'll tell your school everything.
Gimme that.
貸す[かす]:to lend/to loan|to rent out
ちょっと貸せ｡
I'm calling the cops.
That should do it.
これで大丈夫だ｡
念[ねん]:sense|desire|attention, 家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family, 送る[おくる]:to send (a thing)|to take or escort (a person somewhere)|to bid farewell (to the departed)||
念のため 家まで送るよ｡
I'll take you home, just in case.
消す[けす]:to erase|to turn off power|to extinguish|
消して…｡
ん？
Delete it.
Just delete the account. Please.
アカウント:account, 消す[けす]:to erase|to turn off power|to extinguish|
このｱｶｳﾝﾄ もう消して…｡
Hey, uh... Sorry.
その… ごめん｡
It's okay. I got to see a cute side of you.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 見れる[みれる]:to be able to see, 今度[こんど]:this time|next time|recently, 自慢[じまん]:pride/boast
双葉のかわいいとこ見れたから
今度 国見に自慢するわ｡
I'll brag about it to Kunimi when I see him.
Here.
Uh, can you stay with me tonight?
一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, 親[おや]:parent|dealer (in cards, mahjong, etc.)|founder|, 親[しん]:intimacy|close relative|pro- (e.g. pro-American, pro-Japanese, etc.)
その… 今日は一緒にいてほしい｡
親は？
What about your parents?
父親[ちちおや]:father, 学会[がっかい]:scientific society/academic meeting/academic conference, ドイツ:Germany
父親は学会でﾄﾞｲﾂ｡
My father's in Germany
for an academic conference.
And my mother's somewhere
in Europe for business talks too.
母親[ははおや]:mother, 商談[しょうだん]:business discussion/negotiation, ヨーロッパ:Europe
母親も商談でﾖｰﾛｯﾊﾟのどこか｡
That sounds straight out of some TV show.
ドラマ:drama, セリフ:serif, セリフ:speech/words/one's lines
ﾄﾞﾗﾏで聞くようなｾﾘﾌだな｡
It happens often in this family.
一応[いちおう]:more or less|tentatively|just in case|
うちでは よくあるよ｡
一応 言っておくけど
Just to remind you, I am a guy, you know?
僕は男だぞ｡
何かあったら
If you try anything funny,
遠慮[えんりょ]:reserve|declining|forethought, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 報告[ほうこく]:report/information
あることないこと 遠慮なく
桜島先輩に報告する｡
I'll tell Sakurajima-senpai
all about it, and then some.
Just don't embellish the facts, okay?
あることだけにしてくれ｡
Azusagawa?
梓川？
いるよ｡
I'm here.
Azusagawa?
梓川？
いる｡
Here.
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
私は怖かったんだと思う｡
I was probably scared.
今は梓川と国見がいるけど
I may have you and Kunimi now,
ひとり:one person|alone/unmarried, ひとり:incense burner|utensil for carrying live charcoal
いつかまた ひとりに
なるんじゃないかと思って｡
but I was afraid I'd go back
to being alone someday.
高校[こうこう]:senior high school/high school
なんだよ それ｡
高校に入るまでは
What the hell?
I never had these worries
until high school.
不安[ふあん]:anxiety/uneasiness/insecurity
こんな不安はなかった｡
At school or at home,
being alone was the standard for me.
学校[がっこう]:school, 家[いえ]:house|family|lineage, 家[うち, ち]:house/home (one's own)|(one's) family, ひとり:one person|alone/unmarried, ひとり:incense burner|utensil for carrying live charcoal
学校でも家でも
ひとりでいるのが
当たり前[あたりまえ]:natural/reasonable|usual, 高校[こうこう]:senior high school/high school
当たり前だったから｡
それが高校に入って
But once I started high school
and got put in the same class as you two,
同じ[おなじ, おんなじ]:same/identical|(usu. part of a 'nara' conditional) anyway, クラス:class
１年で 梓川と国見と
同じｸﾗｽになって…｡
不安[ふあん]:anxiety/uneasiness/insecurity
それから不安に思うようになった｡
I started feeling anxious.
Kunimi's a rotten guy.
悪い[わるい]:bad|evil|unprofitable||, 悪い[にくい]:hateful/abominable|amazing
国見は悪いやつだな｡
It's half your fault, you know.
半分[はんぶん]:half, 半分[はんぷん]:half minute
半分は梓川だよ｡
I'm amazed you can come to school every day, Azusagawa.
毎日[まいにち]:every day, 学校[がっこう]:school
⦅梓川は よく毎日
学校に来られるね｡
病院[びょういん]:hospital, 送り[おくり]:seeing off|funeral|escapement, うわさ:rumour/rumor/report
病院送りのうわさで
People see you as untouchable
because of the hospitalization incident rumors.
全校[ぜんこう]:the whole school, 生徒[せいと]:pupil, 白い[しろい]:white
全校生徒から
白い目で見られてるのに｡
I'd be thinking too much of myself
if I assumed everyone was avoiding me.
避ける[さける, よける]:to avoid (physical contact with)|to avoid (situation)|to ward off, 自意識[じいしき]:self-consciousness, 過剰[かじょう]:excess/surplus/over-
みんなに避けられてるとか
自意識過剰だろ｡
少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, 過剰[かじょう]:excess/surplus/over-, 頭[とう]:counter for large animals (e.g. head of cattle), 頭[あたま, かしら]:head|hair (on one's head)|mind||
少しも過剰じゃないと思うけど？
頭 大丈夫？
I'm pretty sure that's accurate, actually.
Is your head screwed on right?
On second thought,
I guess you're only here because it isn't.
学校[がっこう]:school
いや ﾀﾞﾒだから
学校に来てるのか｡
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, おもしろい:interesting/fascinating|amusing
双葉って おもしろいな｡
は？ どこが？
You're a funny gal, Futaba.
Huh? How so?
The fact that you're talking to me
shows your head isn't screwed on right either.
話をする[はなしをする]:to have a talk/to tell a story, 時点[じてん]:point in time/occasion, 相当[そうとう]:befitting|considerable|to be worthy of||
僕と こうして話をしている時点で
相当だよ⦆
Oh yeah, I remember that now.
そんなこともあったな｡
I was so scared when Kunimi got a girlfriend.
ものすごい:earth-shattering/staggering|terrible, 怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
国見に彼女ができたとき
ものすごく怖くなった｡
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 悲しむ[かなしむ]:to be sad/to mourn for/to regret, ばっかり:only/merely|approximately
国見は 双葉を
悲しませてばっかりだな｡
Man, all he does is make you sad.
梓川もだよ｡
You're one to talk.
あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25), 美人[びじん]:beautiful woman
あんな美人の彼女ができたら
I thought you'd stop hanging out with me after getting such a pretty girlfriend.
かまう:to mind/to care about|to care for
私になんか
かまってくれなくなると思った｡
Are you stupid?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 一生[いっしょう]:whole life/a lifetime|(the only, the greatest, etc.) of one's life, 友達[ともだち]:friend/companion, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
ｱﾎか 双葉には
一生 友達してもらうつもりで
I'm counting on you to be friends with me for life, you know.
いるんだぞ 僕は｡
Also, you don't understand a thing.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely
あとさ 双葉は
全然わかってないのな｡
惚れる[ほれる]:to fall in love/to be in love/to be charmed with
何が？
国見に惚れてるくせに
About what?
You say you're in love with Kunimi,
but you don't get the guy at all.
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely
ｱｲﾂのこと 全然わかってない｡
スマホ:smartphone/smart phone, 借りる[かりる]:to borrow/to have a loan|to rent
ｽﾏﾎ借りるぞ｡
Let me borrow your phone.
I'll show you how awesome Kunimi is.
You'll fall in love with him all over again.
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 教える[おしえる]:to teach|to tell|to preach, きっと:surely/undoubtedly|sternly, 惚れる[ほれる]:to fall in love/to be in love/to be charmed with, 直す[なおす]:to cure|to fix|to do over again (after -masu base of verb)||
国見のすごさを教えてやる｡
きっと惚れ直すぞ｡
Don't! He'll think I'm crazy for calling at this hour!
やめる:to stop (an activity)/to cease|to cancel, やめる:to resign/to retire/to quit, 非常識[ひじょうしき]:lack of common sense/thoughtlessness/senselessness
やめて！ こんな時間に
非常識だって思われる！
手遅れ[ておくれ]:being (too) late|belated treatment
もう手遅れ｡
Too late.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, ピンチ:crisis/tough spot/predicament
双葉がﾋﾟﾝﾁなんだ｡
すぐに本鵠沼駅まで来てくれ｡
Futaba's in trouble.
Come to Hon-Kugenuma Station at once.
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
What took you so long?
遅い[おそい]:slow|late (e.g. "late at night")|too late|, 早い[はやい]:fast|early (in the day, etc.)|(too) soon|, すぎる:to pass through/to pass by|to pass (i.e. of time)
遅えよ｡
国見が早すぎんの｡
You got here too quickly.
飛ぶ[とぶ]:to fly/to soar|to jump
飛んでこいって言ったの咲太だろ｡
You're the one who told me to come running.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
双葉 大丈夫か？
え？
Futaba, you okay?
Did Sakuta do anything weird to you?
咲太にﾍﾝなことされなかった？
するか！
Like hell!
てっきり:surely/certainly/beyond doubt, 襲う[おそう]:to attack|to succeed (someone in a post, role, etc.)|to make a sudden visit
てっきり 咲太に
襲われたのかと思った｡
I was sure you made a move on her or something.
Why would I call you for help, then?
襲う[おそう]:to attack|to succeed (someone in a post, role, etc.)|to make a sudden visit, 当人[とうにん]:the one concerned/the said person, 通報[つうほう]:report/notification|message (in information and communication theory)
なんで 襲った当人が
通報するんだよ｡
良心[りょうしん]:conscience, 呵責[かしゃく]:blame/accusation/torture, 耐える[たえる]:to bear|to support|to be fit for, かねる:to be unable to/to find difficult (unpleasant, awkward, painful) to do|to serve two or more functions or roles simultaneously
(国見)良心の呵責に
耐えかねて？
Pangs of conscience, maybe?
良心[りょうしん]:conscience
いや 咲太に そんな良心ないか｡
Actually, do you even have one of those?
なんで…｡
Why...
泣かす[なかす]:to make someone cry/to move someone to tears|to grieve
なんで…｡
国見 泣かすなよ｡
Why?
Don't make her cry, Kunimi.
It's my fault?
間違い[まちがい]:mistake|accident|improper conduct (e.g. between man and woman)
俺のせい？
間違いなく国見のせいだな｡
It's definitely your fault.
Welp.
まいる:to go/to come|to be defeated
(国見)まいったな…｡
国見のせいじゃない｡
Not his fault.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 泣き[なき]:weeping/lamenting, 方[かた]:direction|person|method of||, 方[ほう]:direction|side (of an argument, etc.)|type||
双葉って
かわいい泣き方するのな｡
The way you cry is pretty cute, huh?
泣く[なく]:to cry/to weep/to sob, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 久しぶり[ひさしぶり]:a long time (since the last time)/it's been a while (since I last saw, mailed, etc., you)
そんなの知らない
泣くのなんて久しぶりで…｡
Don't ask me.
I haven't even cried in the longest time.
全然[ぜんぜん]:not at all (with neg. verb)|wholly/entirely, ひとり:one person|alone/unmarried, ひとり:incense burner|utensil for carrying live charcoal
でも でも… 私は
全然 ひとりじゃなかったんだ｡
But... But...
I wasn't alone...
I wasn't alone.
ひとり:one person|alone/unmarried, ひとり:incense burner|utensil for carrying live charcoal
ひとりじゃなかった…｡
Sakuta.
咲太｡
あ？
Go buy drinks for me and Futaba.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, ジュース:juice, おごり:luxury/extravagance|treat (i.e. at somebody's expense), おごり:arrogance/haughtiness/conceitedness
俺と双葉に ｼﾞｭｰｽおごりな｡
Why should I have to pay?
搾取[さくしゅ]:exploitation/squeezing/sweating, 意味[いみ]:meaning/significance
僕が搾取される意味がわからん
いっちょんわからん｡
I haven't an inklin'!
Because we need to rehydrate, and you don't.
減る[へる]:to decrease (in size or number)/to diminish/to abate, 水分[すいぶん]:water/liquid/fluid, 補給[ほきゅう]:supply/supplying/replenishment, まずい:poor-quality/shoddy|unskillful, まずい:unappetising/unappetizing|unskillful
(国見)減った水分の補給しないと
まずいだろ｡
Teenage Pig Doesn't
Dream of Bunny Girls
サンキュー:thank you
ほい｡
ｻﾝｷｭｰ｡
Here.
Thanks.
すっかり:all/completely/totally, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 飼いならす[かいならす]:to tame (e.g. animal)/to domesticate
梓川は すっかり
桜島先輩に飼いならされてるね｡
Azusagawa's been totally domesticated by Sakurajima-senpai.
He's devoted in the weirdest ways.
健気[けなげ]:admirable/commendable/praiseworthy
咲太って ﾍﾝなところで
健気だよな｡
で これから どうするよ？
これ｡
Anyway, what's the plan now?
This.
Fireworks Set
風[ふり]:swing|appearance|pretence (pretense)||, 風[かぜ]:wind|manner|cold, 明日[あした, あす]:tomorrow|near future, 夜[よる, よ]:evening/night, 夜[や]:counter for nights, 台風[たいふう]:typhoon/hurricane, らしい:seeming ... (expresses judgment based on evidence, reason or trustworthy hearsay)/appearing ...|-ish
風 強くね？
明日の夜 台風らしいね｡
Isn't the wind too strong?
A typhoon's hitting tomorrow night, apparently.
もっと:(some) more/even more/longer, 寄る[よる]:to approach|to gather (in one place)|to stop by (while on one's way to another place)||
もっと寄れ 国見｡
Scoot in, Kunimi.
Use your huge-ass body to block the wind.
でかい:huge/big/gargantuan, 体[からだ]:body|torso|build||, 体[たい]:body|shape|substance||, 風[ふり]:swing|appearance|pretence (pretense)||, 風[かぜ]:wind|manner|cold
そのでかい体で 風を防げ｡
Y-You're so close.
近い[ちかい]:near|close (in time)|close (relationship)||
ち 近い…｡
Oh, it's lit.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 急ぐ[いそぐ]:to hurry/to rush/to hasten
おっ ついた！
双葉 急げ｡
Hurry, Futaba.
あっ ﾊﾊ…｡
(咲太/国見)お～！
Awesome.
Don't swing it around!
国見は何も聞かないんだね｡
Aren't you going to ask, Kunimi?
Hmm?
ん？
私のこと｡
About me.
呼び出す[よびだす]:to summon/to call (e.g. phone)|to invoke (e.g. subroutine), 何事[なにごと]:what|nothing (with neg. verb)|something or other
咲太に呼び出されたときは
何事かと思ったけどさ
I was wondering what the hell was going on
when Sakuta called me here,
さっき:some time ago/just now, さっき:thirst for blood/bloodlust/determination to kill, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 泣き顔[なきがお]:tear-stained face
さっきの双葉の泣き顔を見たら
もういいやって｡
but when I saw you crying earlier,
I realized it didn't matter.
クッソ:kousso (African flowering plant, Hagenia abyssinica)/kosso/cusso, 負ける[まける]:to lose|to succumb|to be inferior to||
わっ わぁ ｸｯｿ 負けた｡
Damn, I lost.
見える[みえる]:to be seen|to look|to come, 見える[まみえる]:to have an audience|to face (an enemy)|to serve (esp. as one's wife), 花火[はなび]:fireworks, 大会[たいかい]:convention/tournament/mass meeting
こっからだと よく見えそうだな
江の島の花火大会｡
I think you can get a good view of
Enoshima's fireworks show from here.
It's next week, right?
来週[らいしゅう]:next week
来週だろ また３人で見ようぜ｡
Let's see it together again.
Haven't you made plans to go
with your cute girlfriend?
約束[やくそく]:promise|convention|destiny
かわいい彼女と
約束はしてないのかよ？
Uh, we're currently in the middle of a big fight.
只今[ただいま]:Here I am/I'm home!|presently, 只今[しこん]:just now, 絶賛[ぜっさん]:high praise/great admiration/rave reviews, ケンカ:quarrel/brawl/fight
あ～ 只今 絶賛ｹﾝｶ中｡
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder, 約束[やくそく]:promise|convention|destiny
咲太は 桜島先輩と
約束してないの？
Haven't you made plans with Sakurajima-senpai?
只今[ただいま]:Here I am/I'm home!|presently, 只今[しこん]:just now, 事務所[じむしょ]:office, デート:date/go on a date, 禁止[きんし]:prohibition/inhibition/ban, 令[れい]:command/order/dictation, 令[りょう]:administrative and civil code, 発令[はつれい]:official announcement/proclamation
只今 事務所から
ﾃﾞｰﾄ禁止令が発令中｡
Her agency has decreed that we're not allowed to date for the time being.
Well, she is a big-time celebrity.
さすが:as one would expect|still/all the same, さすが:dagger, 超[ちょう, チョー]:super-/ultra-|over (after a number or counter), 人気[にんき]:popularity/public favor|condition (e.g. market), 人気[ひとけ]:sign of life/human presence|humanity, 芸能人[げいのうじん]:performer/entertainer/celebrity
さすが 超人気芸能人｡
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 予定[よてい]:plans/arrangement/schedule
双葉は？
別に予定ない｡
And you, Futaba?
I don't have any plans.
That's that, then.
決まり[きまり]:rule|settlement|habit||
んじゃ 決まり｡
(あくび)
空[から]:emptiness/vacuum/blank, 空[そら]:sky|weather|far-off place||, 明るい[あかるい]:bright|cheerful|familiar (with)|
空 明るくなってね？
Is it just me, or is the sky looking lighter?
徹夜[てつや]:all night/all-night vigil/sleepless night, 初めて[はじめて]:for the first time|only after ... is it .../only when ... do you ...
(理央)こんなふうに徹夜するの
初めて｡
I've never pulled an all-nighter like this before.
私 何やってんだろ…｡
What am I doing?
そりゃ:very/extremely|that is, 確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken
そりゃ ﾊﾞｶなことだろうな｡
確かに ﾊﾞｶなことしてんなぁ｡
Something stupid, obviously.
Yeah, this is pretty stupid, all right.
女子[じょし, おなご]:woman/girl, 女子[めこ, メコ]:vagina|girl
梓川と国見が
女子だったらよかったのに｡
How I wish you two were girls.
始発[しはつ]:first departure (of the day: train, bus, etc.)/first train|departing one's home station (of a train, bus, etc.), 動く[うごく]:to move|to operate|to be touched||
もう始発動いてるな｡
The trains are running now, huh?
Well, cheers.
疲れ[つかれ]:tiredness/fatigue
んじゃ お疲れ またな｡
おう｡
Later.
Yeah.
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid, 一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same
梓川…｡
怖いなら 今日も一緒にいるぞ｡
Azusagawa.
If you're still scared, I'll stay with you today too.
平気[へいき]:coolness/calmness|all right, 一人[ひとり, いちにん]:one person|alone/unmarried
それは平気
もう一人の私のこと｡
Nah, I'm fine.
It's about my other self. She's way worse off.
重症[じゅうしょう]:serious illness, あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener)
重症なのは あっちのほうだよ｡
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener), 嫌い[きらい]:dislike|suspicion|distinction, 嫌い[ぎらい]:dislike/hatred/fear
あっちは 私のこと嫌いだから｡
But she hates me.
So help the other me.
お願い[おねがい]:request/wish|please, 一人[ひとり, いちにん]:one person|alone/unmarried
だから お願い
もう一人の私のこと… お願い｡
Please.
Welcome back.
おかえり:return|welcome home, ただいま:Here I am/I'm home!|presently
おかえり｡
ただいま｡
I'm home.
疲れ[つかれ]:tiredness/fatigue
お疲れだね｡
これ｡
You seem tired.
Here.
アカウント:account, 消す[けす]:to erase|to turn off power|to extinguish|, たぶん:informing, たぶん:perhaps/probably|generous
ｱｶｳﾝﾄは消したって｡
たぶん もうしないと思う｡
She said she deleted the account.
She probably won't do it again.
詳しい[くわしい]:detailed/full|knowing very well, 話す[はなす]:to talk|to tell|to speak (a language)
そう…｡
詳しくは あとで話すよ｡
I see.
I'll fill you in on the details later.
眠い[ねむい]:sleepy/drowsy/somnolent, 寝る[ねる]:to lie down|to go to bed|to sleep (lying down)||
とにかく眠い 寝る｡
But now I'm sleepy. Gonna hit the sack.
Wednesday, August 13
August 13th
Good morning, Onii-chan.
おはようございます:good morning, お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, おはよう:good morning, かえで:maple (tree) (Acer spp.)
おはようございます お兄ちゃん｡
おはよう かえで｡
Morning, Kaede.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 部屋[へや]:room|apartment|stable, 帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home
双葉は部屋？
いえ まだ帰ってません｡
Is Futaba in the room?
No, she isn't back yet.
Huh? She went out?
出かける[でかける]:to go out (e.g. on an excursion or outing)/to leave|to be about to leave
は？ 出かけてるのか？
She said she was going shopping soon after you got back.
お兄ちゃん[おにいちゃん]:familiar form of "older brother"|form of address for young adult male/mister, 帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home, 買い物[かいもの]:shopping/purchased goods
お兄ちゃんが帰ってきてすぐ
買い物に行くって言ってました｡
Shopping?
買い物[かいもの]:shopping/purchased goods
買い物って…｡
[℡]
Damn it! She left her phone here?!
スマホ:smartphone/smart phone, 置く[おく]:to put|to leave (behind)|to establish (an organization, a facility, a position, etc.)||
ｸｿｯ ｽﾏﾎ置いてったのかよ！
Could things get any worse?!
最悪[さいあく]:the worst|in the worst case
最悪だな ｸｿｯ！
What's wrong?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
どしたの？
双葉がいなくなった｡
Futaba's gone. I got home and slept like a log.
帰る[かえる]:to return|to leave|to get home, 爆睡[ばくすい]:sleeping like a log/(being) fast asleep (bombed, crashed), 起きる[おきる]:to get up|to wake up|to occur (usu. of unfavourable incidents)
帰って爆睡して起きたら
When I woke up, she'd disappeared, stuff and all.
荷物[にもつ]:luggage|burden|payload (of a packet, cell, etc.), きれい:pretty/lovely|clean, さっぱり:feeling refreshed/feeling relieved|neat, 消える[きえる]:to go out/to vanish/to disappear
荷物ごと きれいさっぱり
消えてた｡
Just so you know, I don't think we've gone back to being one.
一応[いちおう]:more or less|tentatively|just in case|, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
一応 言っておくけど １人に
戻ったわけじゃないと思う｡
Any idea where she could've gone?
行き先[いきさき, ゆきさき]:destination|whereabouts/address, 心当たり[こころあたり]:having in mind/happening to know of/idea
行き先に 心当たりはないか？
私だったら…｡
If it were me...
Oh, for the love of... What a pain!
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, 面倒[めんどう]:trouble|trouble|care, くさい:stinking/smelly|suspicious, くさい:salvation (from suffering based on Buddha's teachings)
あ～ ｸｿｯ ﾎﾝﾄ面倒くせえ！
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 面倒[めんどう]:trouble|trouble|care, くさい:stinking/smelly|suspicious, くさい:salvation (from suffering based on Buddha's teachings)
双葉 面倒くせえ！
Futaba's such a pain in the ass!
ﾊｧ ﾊｧ…｡
Azusagawa? Why are you here?
梓川 どうして…｡
ひどい:cruel/heartless|violent
ﾊｧ… あ～ ひどい目にあった｡
Damn, what a disaster.
昨日[きのう, さくじつ]:yesterday, 今朝[けさ, こんちょう]:this morning
昨日… ってか 今朝か｡
I forgot to tell you something yesterday... I guess it was this morning.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 忘れる[わすれる]:to forget/to leave carelessly/to be forgetful of, ことがある:(something) has occurred/to have done (something)|(something) happens on occasions
双葉に言い忘れたことがあってさ｡
何？
What?
来週[らいしゅう]:next week, 花火[はなび]:fireworks
来週 花火行かね？
え？
Wanna go see the fireworks next week?
Enoshima's fireworks show.
We went last year, remember?
花火[はなび]:fireworks, 大会[たいかい]:convention/tournament/mass meeting, 去年[きょねん, こぞ]:last year
江の島の花火大会だよ｡
去年も行ったろ？
国見も来るってさ｡
Kunimi said he's coming too.
I...
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
私は…｡
双葉も来るだろ？
You're in, right?
予定[よてい]:plans/arrangement/schedule
行かない｡
何か予定あるのか？
I'm not going.
Do you have plans?
消える[きえる]:to go out/to vanish/to disappear
私はもう ここから消える｡
は？
I'm going to disappear from here.
消える[きえる]:to go out/to vanish/to disappear, 街[がい]:.. street/.. quarter/.. district, 街[まち, ちょう]:town|street|109.09 m||
私は梓川の前から消えるよ｡
この街から消える｡
I'll disappear from your life and this town.
What are you saying?
なんだよ それ｡
世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
この世界に双葉理央は
２人いらない｡
This world isn't big enough for two Futaba Rios.
一人[ひとり, いちにん]:one person|alone/unmarried, なんか:things like .../or something like that ... (often derogatory), なんか:something
もう一人の私は 私なんかより
My other self is doing a much better job
living my life than I ever could.
よっぽど:very/greatly|just about to, 上手[じょうず, じょうて]:skill/skillful|flattery, 上手[うわて, かみて]:upper part|upper stream|right side of the stage (audience's or camera's POV)||, 双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
よっぽど上手に
双葉理央をしている｡
世界[せかい]:the world|sphere|renowned|, なじむ:to become familiar with/to fit in/to adapt oneself
この世界になじんでる｡
She's become a part of this world.
全部[ぜんぶ]:all/entire/whole, 解決[かいけつ]:settlement/solution/resolution
私がいなくなれば
全部 解決する｡
If I go away, it'll solve everything.
解答[かいとう]:answer/solution, 不[ふ]:un-/non-/negative prefix, 不[ぶ]:un-/non-|bad ..., 正解[せいかい]:correct/right/correct interpretation (answer, solution), 間違う[まちがう]:to make a mistake/to be incorrect/to be mistaken
解答としては不正解だな｡
どこも間違ってない｡
As a solution, that's way off the mark.
There's nothing wrong with it.
大[おお]:big/large, 大[だい]:the large part of|big|approximate size||, 間違い[まちがい]:mistake|accident|improper conduct (e.g. between man and woman), 根本[こんげん, ねもと]:root/source/origin, 根本[ねほん]:kabuki script|illustrated kabuki script, 間違う[まちがう]:to make a mistake/to be incorrect/to be mistaken
大間違いだ 根本から間違ってる｡
Everything is wrong with it from the ground up.
Then why'd you take that photo?!
あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25), 写真[しゃしん]:photograph/photo|movie
だったら… なんで あんな写真！
あんな:such (about something or someone distant from both speaker and listener, or about a situation unfamiliar to both speaker and listener)/so/that, あんな:Anna or Anwa era (968.8.13-970.3.25), 羨ましい[うらやましい]:envious (feeling, etc.)/jealous|enviable (position, etc.), 写真[しゃしん]:photograph/photo|movie, 見せる[みせる]:to show/to display
あんな羨ましい写真を
見せられたら そう思うしかない｡
I would've killed to be in that!
What else am I supposed to think after seeing it?!
There's no place for me here anymore!
居場所[いばしょ]:whereabouts/place|place where one belongs, なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation
私の居場所なんて
もうどこにもない！
Nobody needs me.
私は もういらないんだって｡
You and Kunimi won't care as long as you have the other me, right?
あっち:that way (direction distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|that one (something physically distant from both speaker and listener, or something not visible but known by both speaker and listener)
梓川も国見も あっちの私がいれば
いいんでしょ!?
You're an insensitive jerk!
無神経[むしんけい]:insensitive/inconsiderate/callous, いまさら:now (after such a long time)/at this late hour (i.e. it is too late for something)|afresh
梓川は無神経だ！
ｱﾎか いまさら何言ってんだよ｡
Are you stupid? It's too late for that.
無神経[むしんけい]:insensitive/inconsiderate/callous, くらい:dark/gloomy|dark (in colour), くらい:approximately/about|to (about) the extent that
僕が無神経なことくらい
よく知ってるだろ｡
You've always known how insensitive I can be.
Anyway, be there at Kugenuma Beach Station
at 6:30 PM on the 19th.
時半[じはん]:about an hour/short time|half past (the hour), 集合[しゅうごう]:gathering/assembly|set
つうわけで 19日は
鵠沼海岸駅に６時半集合な｡
That's all I have to say.
以上[いじょう]:not less than|beyond ... (e.g. one's means)|above-mentioned||
僕からは以上だ｡
あ…｡
梓川！
Azusagawa?!
Fujisawa General Hospital
Morning.
大雨[おおあめ]:heavy rain, ずぶ濡れ[ずぶぬれ]:soaked/dripping wet
おはよ 大雨の中
ずぶ濡れになって
This is what you get for running around drenched in that downpour.
走る[はしる]:to run|to travel (movement of vehicles)|to hurry to||
走ったりするからよ｡
The tests showed nothing wrong with you.
検査[けんさ]:inspection (e.g. customs, factory)/examination/scan (e.g. MRI, PET, etc.), 結果[けっか]:result/consequence|coming to fruition, 異常[いじょう]:strangeness/abnormality/disorder
検査の結果は異常ないって｡
見とれる[みとれる, みほれる]:to be fascinated (by)/to be captivated by/to be enchanted by
なに見とれてるのよ｡
What are you gawking at?
すごい:terrible/dreadful|amazing (e.g. of strength), 美人[びじん]:beautiful woman, 先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
すごい美人の先輩がいたから
つい…｡
I saw this super hot older girl, so I couldn't help myself.
様子[ようす]:state|appearance|sign
その様子なら もう大丈夫ね｡
I see you're perfectly fine.
麻衣[あさごろも, まい]:linen robe
麻衣さんは なんで
ここにいるの？
Why are you here, Mai-san?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 連絡[れんらく]:to contact|contacting|connection|, もらう:to receive/to take|to get somebody to do something
双葉さんから連絡もらったの｡
Futaba-san called me.
梓川…｡
Azusagawa?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, 迷惑[めいわく, べいこく]:trouble/bother/annoyance, かける:to hang (e.g. picture)/to hoist (e.g. sail)|to sit, かける:to run (race, esp. horse)/to dash|to gallop (one's horse)
双葉にも迷惑かけたな｡
Sorry for causing you trouble.
Seriously. That was cheating.
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, やり方[やりかた]:manner of doing/way/method, 卑怯[ひきょう]:cowardice/meanness/unfairness
ﾎﾝﾄ やり方が卑怯｡
あそこ:there (place physically distant from both speaker and listener)/over there|genitals, 倒れる[たおれる]:to fall|to be forced to bed (by illness, etc.)|to die||, 放つ[はなつ]:to fire (gun, arrow, questions, etc.)|to set free|to emit (e.g. light)||, おける:in/at/for
あそこで倒れられたら
放っておけない｡
How was I supposed to leave you
collapsed back there?
倒れる[たおれる]:to fall|to be forced to bed (by illness, etc.)|to die||, 甲斐[かい]:effect/result/worth, 甲斐[がい]:effect/result/worth
だったら倒れた甲斐もあったな｡
I guess it was worth it, then.
梓川 私は…｡
Azusagawa, I...
You aren't needed anymore?
必要[ひつよう]:necessary/needed|necessity
自分は もう必要ないだとか
丸い[まるい, まろい]:round/circular|harmonious, 収まる[おさまる]:to be in one's place|to be delivered|to be settled||
自分がいなくなれば
すべて丸く収まるだとか
If you go away, it'll solve everything?
But deep down, you're scared and don't know what to do?
怖い[こわい]:scary/frightening|(I'm) afraid
でも 本当は 怖くて
どうすればいいか
面倒[めんどう]:trouble|trouble|care, くさい:stinking/smelly|suspicious, くさい:salvation (from suffering based on Buddha's teachings), 話[はなし]:talk/speech|discussions, 話[わ]:counter for stories, episodes of TV series, etc.
わからないだとか
そういう面倒くさい話なら
I don't wanna hear any more
of that tiresome crap.
もう聞きたくないぞ｡
なんて:how ..!/what ..!|what (questioning), なんて:such as/(things) like|exclamation, 嫌い[きらい]:dislike|suspicion|distinction, 嫌い[ぎらい]:dislike/hatred/fear
自分のことなんて
別に嫌いでいいんだよ｡
There's nothing wrong with hating yourself.
ながら:while/during|while, 生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||
僕は まっ こんなもんだろって
思いながら生きてる｡
I can barely tolerate myself as I live.
You never fail to surprise.
さすが:as one would expect|still/all the same, さすが:dagger
さすがだね｡
Normally, you're supposed to say,
"You can gradually come to love yourself,"
普通[ふつう]:general|normally|local train
普通だと ここは
少し[すこし]:small quantity|little while|short distance, 好き[すき]:liking/fondness/love, 好き[ずき]:-phil/-phile|being attractive (to)
少しずつ 自分を
好きになっていけばいいとか
or, "There are plenty of good things about you,"
or something, aren't you?
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout, いっぱい:one defeat, いっぱい:amount necessary to fill a container (e.g. cupful, spoonful, etc.)/drink (usu. alcoholic)|full
双葉にもいいところは
いっぱいあるとか
前向き[まえむき]:facing forward/front-facing/forward-looking, 生きる[いきる]:to live|to make a living|to be in effect||, 方[かた]:direction|person|method of||, 方[ほう]:direction|side (of an argument, etc.)|type||
言うべきなんじゃないの？
そんな前向きな生き方
Having such a positive mindset will only wear you out.
疲れる[つかれる]:to get tired|to be worn out (e.g. of well used objects)|to starve, 最低[さいてい]:least|worst|awful|
疲れるだけだろ｡
最低だね 梓川は｡
You're the worst, Azusagawa.
ほっと:feeling relieved/(sigh of) relief
だけど… なんか ほっとする｡
But that takes a load off my mind.
ホント:truth/reality/actuality, ほっと:feeling relieved/(sigh of) relief
ﾎﾝﾄ ほっとするね｡
I really feel at home with you.
あのさ…｡
ん？
Hey...
花火[はなび]:fireworks
花火 私も行っていい？
ﾀﾞﾒだな｡
Can I go see the fireworks with you?
Nope.
言い方[いいかた]:way of talking/speaking style
そんな言い方じゃﾀﾞﾒだ｡
Not if you have to ask.
花火[はなび]:fireworks
わ 私も花火行きたい！
I-I wanna go see the fireworks too.
相手[あいて]:companion|other party|opponent (sports, etc.), 間違える[まちがえる]:to make a mistake (in)/to commit an error (e.g. in calculation)|to confuse
言う相手 間違えてる｡
え？
You're telling the wrong person.
It's me.
(理央)私… うん｡
Yeah, I met up with Azusagawa.
会[え]:gathering (esp. Buddhist, festive, etc.), 会[かい]:meeting/assembly|association
梓川には会えた｡ それで その…｡
Anyway, uh...
I have a request.
お願い[おねがい]:request/wish|please
お願いがあるんだけど｡
一緒[いっしょ]:together|at the same time|same, 花火[はなび]:fireworks
私も一緒に花火行きたい｡
I want to go see the fireworks together.
Hello?
診察室[しんさつしつ]:examining room, 戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
[℡](理央)梓川は もう診察室に
戻りなよ｡
Go back to the examination room, Azusagawa.
You're keeping Sakurajima-senpai waiting.
先輩[せんぱい]:senior (at work or school)/superior/elder
[℡]桜島先輩が待ってるんでしょ？
戻る[もどる]:to turn back (e.g. half-way)|to return|to recover (e.g. something lost)|, 戻る[もとる]:to go against/to act contrary to/to deviate from
１人に戻ったんだな｡
[℡]うん…｡
You became one again?
Yeah.
Anyway, you'd better not be late for the fireworks.
花火[はなび]:fireworks, 遅刻[ちこく]:lateness/late coming
[℡]それより花火
梓川 遅刻しないでよ｡
Gotcha.
わかった｡
August 19th
Hey.
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
お～い 双葉！
Futaba.
メガネ:spectacles/glasses, 戻す[もどす]:to put back|to vomit|to recover (of a market price), おかしい:funny/amusing|strange
ﾒｶﾞﾈ 戻したんだ？
お おかしい？
You brought back the glasses?
D-Do they look weird?
浴衣[ゆかた, よくい]:yukata (light cotton kimono worn in the summer or used as a bathrobe), 合う[あう, おう]:to come together|to fit|to be profitable|
浴衣に合ってるよ｡ なっ 咲太？
You look great in that yukata.
Right, Sakuta?
It's kinda sensual.
エロい:erotic/pornographic|eminent, 確か[たしか]:sure|reliable|If I'm not mistaken
なんかｴﾛい｡ なっ 国見？
まぁ 確かに｡
Right, Kunimi?
You've got a point there.
浴衣[ゆかた, よくい]:yukata (light cotton kimono worn in the summer or used as a bathrobe), 嫌[いや, や]:disagreeable/detestable/unpleasant
だから 浴衣は嫌だったの｡
This is why I didn't want to wear a yukata.
Kunimi.
国見…｡
ん？
何？
(花火の音)
What?
Futaba, I...
双葉[ふたば]:bud/sprout
双葉 俺…｡
返事[へんじ]:reply/answer/response
返事はいいよ わかってるから｡
そっか｡
Don't bother with an answer.
I know what it'll be.
Really?
And I'll probably start crying
if you say anything right now.
泣く[なく]:to cry/to weep/to sob
何か言われたら
私 泣くと思うし｡
浴衣[ゆかた, よくい]:yukata (light cotton kimono worn in the summer or used as a bathrobe), 貸す[かす]:to lend/to loan|to rent out
そしたら 咲太が
浴衣のすそを貸してくれるってさ｡
Sakuta says he'll offer you
his yukata sleeve if you do.
鼻[はな]:nose
鼻かんでいいぞ｡
ﾊﾞｰｶ｡
You can blow your nose on it.
Dumbass.
Kunimi.
国見｡
ん？
Make up with your girlfriend.
仲直り[なかなおり]:reconciliation/make peace with
彼女と仲直りしなよ｡
You probably fought over me or Azusagawa, right?
どうせ:anyhow/in any case|at best, 原因[げんいん]:cause/origin/source
どうせ 私か梓川が原因でしょ｡
電話[でんわ]:telephone call/phone call|telephone (device)
ああ あとで電話してみよっかな｡
Yeah. I guess I'll call her later.
Alarm
That's my Sakuta. Stupid pig.
Next Episode
#9: Sister Panic